## Fajesha Nasim

(832) 247-2949 | fajesha@gmail.com | Houston, TX linkedin.com/in/fajesha-a3918224a

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Detail-oriented problem solver with 460+ training hours and experience developing full stack Java applications (in training). Interested in securing a Junior software Developer role that will allow me the opportunity to excel in computer programming, software and web development, while employing analytical, communication, and leadership skills.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Web3Schools JavaScript Certification (in progress; expected date of completion 12/2022)

- Java
- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS3
- Spring Boot
- Informix

- Spring Data JPA
- Spring Security (JWT)
- Bootstrap
- REST API's
- SQL/MS SQL server
- Oracle database
- Unit Testing (JUnit, Mockito)
- SOLID OOP Principles
- Dependencies Injection
- Git (version control software)

**EXPERIENCE** 

**Generation Junior Full Stack Java Developer Program** | Remote | August 2022- December 2022 *Training Participant (in progress)* 

- Participating in a 16-week, 460+ hour Junior Full Stack Java Developer program that emphasizes hands-on practical application
- Learning and deploying the technologies involved in creating full stack web applications with Java using Spring Boot Frameworks, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3
- Implementing basic unit tests and deploying the application to Heroku

PROS Revenue Management | Houston, TX | March 2000 - December 2002 Java programmer

Broadcast Revenue Management System

- Assisted in the software development of the full life-cycle of Broadcast Revenue Management System which helps clients to price their product, and accurately advertise time by managing demand based on revenue management principles
- Developed GUI for different modules in Java for applying the business rules and data retrieval and updates from the Oracle database
- Coordinated in designing web pages using JSP, Java script and XML. The system applied XSL transformations on them to produce HTML to be displayed. Tomcat was used as the application server

**Central Statistical Organization** | Doha, Qatar | May 1997 - April 1998 **Informix Programmer** 

Statistical Report Generation for "Annual Statistical Abstract, State of Qatar"

- Drafted statistical reports on population, industrial activities, health, education etc. from Informix database
- Forumalted Reports in Informix and designed SQL queries to retrieve information

## **EDUCATION**

**Master of Science in Statistics** Mangalore University, India Second Rank holder in the university

**Bachelor of Science in Computer Science** Mangalore University, India Graduated with Honors